moneyextra.com 2014-11-22

# Privacy Policy - Moneyextra.com

## Privacy Policy

Moneyextra.com Limited is a company within Fairpoint Group Plc. We are committed to keeping your information private. This document describes our privacy policy. 

  1. What information do we collect about you?
  2. How do we use your information?
  3. Safeguard of information
  4. Recording of calls
  5. Identification checks
  6. Access to your personal information
  7. Use of cookies
  8. Other websites

#### 1\. What information do we collect about you?

In order to provide you with products and services we need to collect, use, share and store personal and financial information about you. We hold the personal data provided by you during the voluntary registration process to tailor our service to your specific interests and requirements. We also hold the personal data provided by you in relation to certain services on the Website (such as the Portfolio Manager), so that you do not need to re-enter this data when you next require the service. Clearly, the more complete and accurate the personal data we hold about you, the better our service will be.

We only hold your personal data where you have been issued with a personalised user name and password. These are unique to each registered user. You should take great care of them and keep them safe at all times. We will collect further information if you contact us with comments or specific requests.

We may also use cookies. For an explanation, see our policy on cookies.

#### 2\. How do we use your information?

We will use your information to provide our services, to prevent and detect fraud, money laundering and other crime, carry out regulatory checks and meet our obligations to any relevant regulatory authority, and to develop and improve our services to you and other customers and protect our interests. The nature of our service means that from time to time we have to share your personal data with our affiliates who provide the products and services that you request. For instance, if you want to apply for a particular financial product after using the comparison service or simply require more information about it, we will pass your relevant personal data to the product provider in order to fulfil your request.

The cookies information is used to help us understand more about how our website is used and to improve our site.

We will retain information about you after the closure of your file for as long as permitted for legal, regulatory, fraud and other financial crime prevention and legitimate business purposes.

We may use your personal information for market research and other marketing purposes, which may include sharing it with other companies within the Fairpoint Group Plc. In order to provide you with products and services this information will be held in our data systems or the data systems of our agents or subcontractors. We would also like to keep you informed of selected products and services available from us and our carefully chosen suppliers. We may do this by post or by phone unless you have told us not to; and by email, text or other electronic means if you have told us that we can or as otherwise allowed by law. If your personal details change or you would prefer to no longer receive this information from us please [email us](mailto:customer%2Eservices%40moneyextra%2Ecom). However, please remember that by opting out, we will not be able to contact you about products or services that may benefit you.

We will keep information about you confidential unless you have consented to its transfer to any other third party, we have a duty to disclose it or law or regulation allows us to do so for legitimate business purposes.

#### 3\. Safeguard of information

We regularly review our security standards and procedures to help prevent unauthorised access to personal information, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification and unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

#### 4\. Recording of calls

For training purposes, any calls with us may be recorded and may be monitored.

#### 5\. Identification checks

In cases where legislation requires us to carry out an identification check, we will validate your name, address and other personal information supplied by you against an appropriate third party database. You should advise us if you do not consent to such a check being made. In performing these checks personal information provided by you may be disclosed to a registered Credit Reference Agency which may keep a record of that information. The checks are only to confirm your identity. A credit check is not performed and your credit rating will be unaffected. All information provided by you will be treated securely and strictly in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

#### 6\. Access to your personal information

You have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. In accordance with our Data Protection Policy, we charge £10 for all information requests to cover administration costs.

Please address requests to:

The Data Protection Officer 

Fairpoint Group Plc

Fairclough House 

Church Street 

Adlington 

Lancashire

PR7 4EX

#### 7\. Use of Cookies

What Are Cookies?

Cookies are tiny text files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. ClearStart uses cookies to improve the performance of our websites to ensure we provide our customers with the best possible web site experience.

The cookies we use can’t harm your computer and we don’t store any personally identifiable information. The information we gather is used to improve the customer experience of the site, for example they are used to determine errors and display relevant content.

For more information about how we use cookies please see our Cookies Policy page

#### 8.Other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites, you should read their own privacy policies.
